抱歉 抱歉 路上堵车了
Sorry, there was traffic jam.
最讨厌早班了
I hate the morning shift.
他们吐得到处都是
There was always vomit everywhere.
就像前几天在七子通公园厕所一样…
Like the other day at Nanago Dori Park...
就在涩谷的幡谷
...in Hatagaya.
真是太可怕了
It was truly terrible.
还有个昏迷很久的人
There is someone who has been out for a long time.
太恐怖了 十分可以打八分
The horror level is 8 out of 10!
你在听我说话吗
Are you listening to me?
不用麻烦了 桧山先生 反正没过多久还是会变脏
No need to bother, Mr. Hiyarama. It'll get dirty again later.
妈妈
Mom!
怎么了
What is it?
是妈妈带你过来的吗
Are you here with your mother?
不会有事儿的
Everything will be fine.
仗助
Josuke?
妈妈正在找你呢
Mom is looking for you!
你是什么人啊
Where are you from?
妈妈在到处找你呢
Mom is looking for you everywhere!
我不是跟你说不要走得太远吗
Didn't Mom say not to go too far?
我在公园里到处找你呢
Mom is looking all over the park.
对不起 妈妈
I'm sorry Mom, dear.
现在弟弟也哭了
Now he was crying too.
对不起 妈妈
I'm sorry mom.
现在好了
Now it's fine.
这要怎么用
How does this work?
谢谢
Thank you very much.
你好 欢迎光临
Hello, welcome.
欢迎
Welcome back!
犒劳一下你
For your hard work!
太好了 他打中了
Yes! He hit the ball!
是吧 没错吧
He's in, right?
你看到了没
He's in! Did you see?
嘿 你干嘛
Hey, what are you doing?
打赌吗 这有什么好玩儿的
Playing bets? Where's the fun?
凯酱 退后
Kat-chan! Back off!
你要尊重别人支持的队伍或者是宗教什么的 来击个掌
Always respect other people's sports teams or religions. High five!
现在回去吧
Now go away. All right.
他们作弊了
They cheated.
他们把其他队里厉害的球手挖走了
They steal great players from other teams.
天啊
Good grief!
绫 你来啦
Aya! You come!
百分之百的惊喜
What a surprise! The rating is 10 out of 10!
稍等 还剩最后一个地方了
Wait a moment! This is the last place.
马上就结束了
I'm about to finish!
看来你还是能很有效率地工作呀
Turns out you can work fast.
有个女孩在等我呢 我要下班了
There's a girl waiting for me. I'm done for today.
快点
Come on!
桧山先生 你的车能借我用一下吗
Mr Hiyarama, may I borrow your car?
拜托了 我可不能错过今天晚上的机会
I can't miss this opportunity tonight. Mr. Hiyarama, please!
求你了
I beg you.
拜托
Come on, please.
这是我的前辈 桧山先生
This is Mr. Hiyarama, my senior at work.
认真勤勉 而且还很安静
Hard worker, but very quiet.
可没有人这么说过我
I don't even know what it sounds like.
桧山先生 这是绫
Mr. Hiyarama, this is Aya.
绝对的满分女孩
Definitely a 10 out of 10!
别这么说了
Stop saying that.
这个还能放吗
Can this be done?
桧山先生...
Pak Hiyarama..
我喜欢这个声音
I like the sound.
是吗
Time?
史密斯
Smith?
很常见的名字
Very common name.
桧山先生...
Pak Hiyarama,...
…你真的喜欢这份工作吗
...do you really like this job?
你甚至有自己的设备和工具
You have your own equipment and tools.
这种工作你为什么还要这么努力呢
How can you work so hard at a job like this?
不必回答我
You don't have to answer it.
我只是好奇
I'm just curious.
这个人很奇怪
This person is strange.
满分十分可以打九分
The scale is oddly 9 out of 10.
我喜欢盒式磁带的声音
I like the sound of cassette recordings.
是的 卡带的声音听起来很棒
Yes! The cassette sounds great!
这是我第一次听
This is my first time listening to it.
第一次总是最好的
The first time is always good!
在那儿把我放下
Drop me off there.
我们不是在约会吗
Aren't we on a date?
酒吧要加班
I have an extra shift at the bar.
你来的话 我可以陪你一晚上
If you come, I'll be with you all night.
我还没发工资呢
I'm still waiting for my salary.
桧山先生 这对我来说非常重要
Mr. Hiyarama, this is very important to me.
人没钱的话还谈什么恋爱啊
People can't fall in love without money.
这个世界到底怎么了
What happened to this world?
这就是现代吗
Is this the modern era?
这个值多少钱啊
What is the price for this?
你不想知道吗
Don't you want to know?
我只是好奇
I'm just curious!
这些东西又流行起来了 没准儿这些很值钱呢
Analog is back in trend. All of this may be of great value.
我真的只是好奇而已 我知道下北有一个估价地地方
I'm really just curious! I know a suitable place in Shimokita.
我不去
I didn't go there.
都用不上三十分钟
It only takes less than 30 minutes.
应该就在这里的...
It should be here...
就在这里 看到了吧
Here, that's the sign.
借过
Excuse me.
请问 这个现在值多少
Excuse me, how much is the selling price for this?
卢·里德的磁带很少见啊
This one is rare, it's Lou Reed.
这个的话值12000日元
For this, 12 thousand yen.
真的吗
Very?
- 这个值8000  - 真的吗
- For this 8000.   - Really?
这些磁带你是从哪儿弄到的
Where did you get these tapes?
都是我的前辈的
They belong to my seniors.
这个得有4000日元
This one is 4000 yen.
这盘差不多6000 你手里的这些值很多钱呢
This one can be sold for 6000. You can make a lot of money from all this.
这还只是估计
This is my estimate.
我的天啊
My goodness!
桧山先生 我们把这些都卖掉吧
Extraordinary! Mr. Hiyarama, let's sell all of this!
谁的我们都要 现在这个很流行
We accept everything. Cassettes are trending.
尤其是七八十年代的磁带
Especially cassettes from the 70s and 80s.
我们把你的收藏都卖了吧
We have to sell it, your entire collection.
光是这盘就值12000
Twelve thousand just for this tape!
现在正是时候
Now is the perfect time!
一个 就卖一个也行
OK, just one. We'll just sell one.
然后我就可以去酒吧见绫了 今晚对我真的很重要
Then I can go to the bar to meet Aya. This is a very important night for me.
真的很重要
This is a very important night for me!
如果我错过这个机会...
If I miss this opportunity...
没有钱还哪有什么爱情生活 是吧
No love life if we're broke? Is that so?
非常感谢
Thank you very much!
恩人 我先走了
You saved me! I go first!
你最棒了 桧山先生
You're the best, Mr. Hiyarama!
欢迎下次光临
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你
Thank You!
桧山先生...
Pak Hiyarama..
我觉得我跟绫不会在一起了 大概只有两成的机会
I don't think it's possible for me to be with Aya. Chances are 2 out of 10.
但是我不会放弃的放弃
But that doesn't mean I give up.
桧山先生...
Pak Hiyarama..
你还没结婚吧
You're not married yet, right?
你这个年纪还一个人
Alone at your age..
不会觉得孤独吗
Don't you ever feel lonely?
高志
Takashi!
是你
It's you!
高志
Takashi!
- 我们已经很久没见面了  - 高志
- We haven't seen each other for a long time.  - Takashi!
你好吗
How are you?
我在找你呢
I am looking for you.
- 真的吗  - 是啊
- Very?   - Yes.
桧山先生 这是我的好朋友寺酱
Mr. Hiyarama, this is Dera-chan, my good friend.
你看到了吧 他很喜欢我的耳朵
As you can see, he likes my ears.
每次见面都会握住
Every time he meets me, he holds it.
而且不管我到哪里 他总是能找到我
He always finds me. 10 out of 10.
他喜欢我的耳朵 ...
Dera-chan likes my ears,...
我都要变成什么挂件了
...and I'm just the accessory, right?
- 是的 - 是吧
- Yes. -  Isn't it?
我要把这个还给你
I want to return this.
给你
Here he is.
我能再听一遍吗
Can I listen to it again?
谢谢
Thank You.
贵司有跟你说什么吗
Did Takashi tell you something?
欢迎
Welcome.
这是犒劳你的
For your hard work!
谢谢
Thank You.
文库新书 每本100日元
100 YEN FOR THE BOOKS
幸田文【日本女作家】应该更出名的
Aya Koda should be more famous.
虽然她的遣词很日常 但是依旧很特别
He uses common word choices, but is still special.
晚上好 桧山先生
Good evening, Mr. Hiyarama.
还是老样子吗
The usual message?
你现在在读什么
What are you reading now?
幸田文的木
Aya Koda "Pohon".
散文吗
The essay?
你读过吗
Have you read it?
你很有学识
You're very educated.
我可不这么觉得
No, I don't think so.
这是你的土豆沙拉...
Here's your potato salad...
还有酒水...
...and here's to a long day.
老板娘 我们怎么都没有前菜
Mom, we didn't get the appetizer.
怎么会 肯定有的
I'm sure I have.
那也没有这么多
We never got that much.
不会的 我对大家可是一视同仁的
That is not true. We're all equal here, right?
那我可得去字典里查查这个词
I had to look up the word "equality" in the dictionary.
女人可不喜欢多嘴的男人
Women don't like talkative men.
你这里一直有皱纹吗
Have you always had wrinkles here?
不 就一个 在那里
No, the only one. There.
老板娘 还有炸豆腐吗
Mama, do you have fried tofu?
已经卖光了  你要的话我一会儿去做
No, it's finished. I'll make it later if you buy it.
他的妻子丢下他走了
His wife left him, you know.
他怎么还这么开心呢
How could he be so cheerful?
你们是在说我吗
Are you talking about me?
没有
There isn't any.
为什么我的妻子离开我了 我还这么高兴
How can you be cheerful when your wife left you?
很简单啊 因为我终于可以没有负担地一个人生活了
That is easy. Finally I can live alone again without burdens.
任谁都会很开心的
It makes all men happy.
能够摆脱挑挑拣拣的女人真是一种解脱
It's a relief to be able to get rid of fussy women.
还强撑着呢
You pretend to be strong.
过不了多久 你就要跟老板娘哭诉你有多孤独了
Soon you will confide in Mama how lonely you are.
左不过是些无聊的故事
Just boring stories.
要再来一杯吗
Want another drink?
请
Please.
为什么世界上没有能保持不变的事物呢
Why can't everything stay the same?
老板娘
Mama.
给我们唱那首歌吧
Sing us that song.
我们的最爱
Our favorite.
哦 那首啊
Oh yes!
但桧山先生才刚到
But Mr. Hiyarama had just arrived.
别让我们难过呀
Don't disappoint us.
就是呀
Well, that's it.
来吧
Come on.
既然你已经拿出吉他了...
Since you've already got the guitar out... Come on.
这是一首优美的歌曲
This is a beautiful song.
我到了一个叫
I got to the place
新奥尔良的地方
in New Orleans
到了一家叫旭日之屋
to a place called a brothel
的妓院
"House of the Rising Sun"
我爱的男人
The man I love
他没有回来
he didn't come back.
就在那时我离开了
That's when I left
你的祖国
your homeland.
我上了火车
I got on the train,
没有回头...
and in a matter of seconds...
还有两杯柠檬水
And two lemonades!
你来啦 稍等一下
You've arrived, just wait a moment!
给你
For your hard work!
叔叔
Uncle.
你从哪来的
Where are you from?
我已经等你很久了
I've been waiting for you for a long time.
你家是哪扇门
Which door is your house?
楼上还是楼下
Upstairs or downstairs?
是Niko吗
Niko?
你长这么大了
You're big!
叔叔...
Uncle,...
…你要上班吗
...you're going to work?
我可以一起去吗
can i come along
你应该让我跟着的
Uncle should let me come along.
我一个人的话可不知道会做出什么事情
I don't know what I would do if I was alone.
从那边上
Enter from the next door.
你想要咖啡吗
Would you like coffee?
要
Of.
和我一样吗
The same as me?
好
Of.
谢谢
Thank You.
- 你要放进去吗  - 是的
- Do you want to set it? - Yes.
不 不
No, no.
是这边
This side.
- 像这样吗  - 是的
- Like this?  -  Yes.
磁带卷在这边
The tape is on this side.
是东京晴空塔吗
What is Sky Tree tower?
是的
Oh, benar.
那么 这就是盒式录音带
So, this is a cassette?
是你那个年代的吗
From ancient times?
是啊
From ancient times.
我能在 iPhone上播放吗
Can I play this on my iPhone?
这写的是什么
What is it written?
范·莫里森
Van Morrison.
Spotify上有吗
Is this on Spotify?
我也不懂
Uncle doesn't know.
那是什么
Where's that?
什么
What?
你说的那家店
That shop.
那不是一家商店
It's not a shop.
哇 这个
Ah, that!
你是说这个吗  我的相机已经很旧了
You mean this? My camera is quite old.
看
Look!
怎么可能
How could that be?
你不记得了吗
You do not remember?
是你送我的 叔叔
You gave it to me, Uncle.
- 啊 是啊  - 说谎
- Oh yes. - Lie.
你不记得了 对吧
You don't remember, do you?
这棵树是你的朋友吗
Is the tree your friend?
朋友吗
Friend?
难道不是吗
Is it true?
是啊 你说得对
You are right.
这是我的树...朋友
This is my friend.. Tree.
叔叔
Uncle?
我可以借这本书吗
can i borrow this book
哪一本
Which one?
十一篇短篇小说
"Eleven Short Stories."
当然
Of course.
波兰龟那篇里的男孩 维克多…
This boy, Victor, from the tale "The Polam Turtle"...
他就跟我一样
He's like me.
我能理解他正在经历什么
I understand what he is going through.
我能帮你吗
can i help
谢谢
Thank You.
叔叔 你为什么跟妈妈合不来啊
Uncle, why don't you and mother get along?
她这么说的吗
He told you that?
每次我谈到你...
Every time I talk about you...
她都会转移话题
...he changed the topic.
这样啊
So.
你和妈妈吵架了吗
Did you quarrel with your mother?
差不多吧
Something like that.
你总是离家出走吗
Do you always run away from home?
这是第一次
This is my first time.
我一直计划着跟叔叔一起生活
It was always my plan to stay with Uncle.
哈哈 这算什么
What does that mean?
谢谢 我是去那边吗
Thank You. Am I coming here?
- 十分钟后见  - 这也太短了
- See you in 10 minutes. - That's too short.
那就二十分钟
Then 20 minutes.
是的 我明白
Yes. I understand.
嗯 知道
Yes, good.
你饿了吗
Are you hungry?
- 我们去吃午饭吧  - 太好了
- Then we'll have lunch.  -  Hooray!
- 毛巾放这里  - 谢谢
- Put the towel here. - Thank You.
你和妈妈一点都不像
Uncle and mother are nothing alike.
你指的是哪方面
You mean?
她说我们是不同世界的人
He said Uncle and we live in different worlds.
这应该是真的吧
That's probably true.
真的吗
Is it true?
这个世界就是这样形形色色
This world consists of many different worlds.
相关联的 不相关的
Some are related and some are not.
我的世界...
My world...
跟你母亲的世界非常不同
...and your mother's world is very different.
那我呢
What about my world?
我身处哪个世界呢
Where in the world am I?
这条河会流入大海吗
This river flows into the ocean?
是的
Yes, to the ocean.
你要去那里吗
Are you going there?
下次吧
Next time.
什么时候
When is it?
下次就是下次
Next time, next time.
具体呢
When exactly?
下次就是下次
Next time, next time.
现在就是现在
Now yes now.
下次 下次
Next time, next time.
现在 现在
Now yes now.
下次 下次
Next time, next time.
现在 现在
Now yes now.
下次 下次
Next time, next time.
现在 现在
Now yes now.
姐姐
Sister.
好久不见
Long time no see.
你就住在这里吗
So you live here?
我没有恶意 Niko 拿上你的东西
I don't mean anything bad. Niko, get your things.
- 我不要  - 我不是在跟你商量
- Don't want to!  - That's not an option.
叔叔
Uncle!
赶快
Hurry up.
叔叔
Uncle!
只要你愿意 你随时都可以来
Come visit whenever you want.
你的书我还没读完呢
I haven't even finished reading your book.
带着吧
Just bring it.
我会像维克多一样
I will be like Victor.
不会的
Won't.
- 别这么说  - Niko
- Do not say like that.   - Niko!
给你添麻烦了
Here's to your trouble.
是你最喜欢的巧克力
Your favorite chocolate.
她是个好孩子
He is a good child.
我可不敢说
I'm not sure about that.
我们的父亲...
Our father...
他已经什么都不认识了
...he doesn't recognize anything anymore.
你要去疗养院探望他吗
Are you going to visit him at the nursing home?
他再也不会和以前一样了
He will never be the same.
你真的在清扫厕所吗
Is it true that you work cleaning toilets?
叔叔
Uncle.
谢谢
Thank You.
你好 我是高志
Hello, this is Takashi.
我是高志 你好
This is Takashi, hello?
我听到了
I hear you.
桧山先生 您对我很好 对此 我真的非常感激
Mr. Hiyarama, you have been kind to me. I really appreciate it.
满分十分可以打九分
The rating is 9 out of 10!
所以我很难当面跟你讲 我辞职了
That's why it's hard for me to say this, but I resign.
什么
What?
钱我会马上还你的
I will immediately reimburse you.
等等 那谁来替你
Wait, what about your sif?
你好
Of.
我们短期内找不到替代者
We can't find a replacement anytime soon.
那我应该怎么办
No replacement? What should I do?
那你今天就只能加班了
You have to fill the shift today.
抱歉 我会很快的
what can Sorry, I'll be brief.
抱歉
Sorry.
你好
Excuse me!
- 你是新来的吗  - 我马上结束了
- Are you new?   - I'm about to finish.
怎么了
What is it?
他人呢
Where's Takashi?
我已经打过三遍电话了 为什么没人接
I've called three times. Why isn't anyone picking up?
我只能顶一天
I'm just doing it for today.
赶紧找个新人
Find someone, okay?
我是佐藤 是被派到这里的...
I'm Sato. I was told to come here immediately...
...来顶替之前的人的班次
...and took over the shift from the previous employee.
是从那里开始吗
Should I start there?
是的
Of.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello - Hello.
你还记得这之前是什么吗
Do you remember what this used to be?
我们已经老了
That means we are old.
帕特里夏·海史密斯【美国女作家】对焦虑了如指掌
Patricia Highsmith knows all about anxiety.
她告诉读者恐惧和焦虑完全是不同的东西
He showed me that fear and anxiety are different things.
你这人是怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
就是..
You know..
我能进来吗
can i come in
进来吧
Come in.
跟香烟一起打包好了
Packed cigarettes and plastic.
我可以来一只吗
Can I have one?
我已经很久没有抽烟了
I haven't smoked for a long time.
刚才的那个人是你吗
Did you see us at the bar earlier?
看来你是个常客
It seems like you always go there.
是的
Of.
从开业至今已有五六年了
It's been five or six years since the place opened.
这样
So it turns out.
那是一个很好的地方
It's a beautiful place.
我是她的前夫
I'm her ex-husband.
我知道
I understand.
我们离婚已经快七年了
It's been about seven years since we divorced.
我已经再婚了
I've remarried.
距离上次见他已经七年了
It's been seven years since I last saw him.
我得了癌症
I have cancer.
癌细胞一直在扩散
The cancer has spread.
我的身体因为化疗十分不堪
My body was swollen from chemotherapy.
然后我...
Then I...
……突然觉得自己欠她一个道歉
...suddenly felt that I owed him an apology.
以为我挺过去了
Nothing bad happened.
也许不是道歉
Maybe not an apology.
我要感谢她
I want to thank him.
可能也不是
No, it's not about that either.
我就是想见见她 仅此而已
I just want to see him, that's all.
来一瓶吗
Do you want a drink?
还剩一瓶
I still have one more.
现在吗...
In that case,...
好啊
...I'll take one.
请照顾好她
Please take care of her.
- 不 我们不是那种关系  - 拜托你了
- No, we don't have that kind of relationship.  - I'm counting on you.
我只是一个食客
We don't have a relationship like that.
那些阴影..
Shadow..
被覆盖之后会变得更黑吗
Do they get darker when overwritten?
谁知道你
Who knows.
我还有那么多不理解的事情呢
There are so many things I don't understand.
生命就这样结束了
That's how life ends.
真不甘心啊
I think so.
那现在就去验证一下吧
Let's find out now.
什么
What?
站在那
Stand there.
什么
What?
你看到了什么
What do you see?
看起来一样啊
Looks the same.
不是更黑了吗
Isn't it darker?
没有吧
Probably not.
对我来说这看起来更黑了
That looks darker to me.
我是看不出有什么区别
I don't see the difference.
在这里 看
Here, look!
颜色要深一点才有意义
The shade needs to be darker to make sense!
你真是太执着了
You're so persistent.
还是没什么变化
Still no changes?
算了吧
Just forget it.
抱歉
I agree.
玩儿追影子吗
Want to play with shadows?
我来追
I'm the one chasing.
准备好了吗
Ready?
我要开始了
I start.
跑吧
Run!
- 你还好吗  - 太难了
- Are you okay? -  This is difficult.
现在换我
Now I'm the one chasing.
- 你确定吗 准备好了吗  - 我要开始了
- Are you sure? Ready?  - I start.
得手了
Got it!
太难了
Very difficult.
很累人啊 踩到了
This is tiring. Got it!
- 很接近了 我踩到你了  - 真的吗
- That's close. I stepped on you.   - Is it true?
翻译：霓虹狮子_